

# **About**

I'm a Data Scientist with a versatile scientific background, thanks to my studies in physics & blockchain technologies and my experience as a fullstack developer.

In my spare time I teach physics and mathematics to High School students as a freelancer.

A curiosity about me: I was a professional trained cook (also experienced in restaurant reception) as I studied Hospitality in High School.

That allowed me to work abroad while I was teenager, granting me memorables experiences with several people of different cultures.

# Education

O 2024 - in progress **BACHELOR IN ECONOMICS** 

Università degli Studi di Roma La Sapienza, Rome, Italy

🗘 2022 - 2023 🖳 **DATA STRUCTURES & ALGORITHMS SPECIALIZATION** 

University of California San Diego, US

**O** 2022 - 2023 🖪 **DATA SCIENCE SPECIALIZATION** 

IBM, New York, United States

2019 - in progress **BACHELOR IN PHYSICS** 

Università degli Studi di Milano Bicocca, Milan, Italy

# 🕰 Languages

**ITALIAN (C2) ENGLISH (C1)** SPANISH (B2) FRENCH (B2)

### Contact









I hereby give consent for my personal data included in the application

 $to \ be \ processed \ for \ the \ purposes \ of \ future \ recruitment \ processes.$ 

# Maurizio Falconi

### Data Scientist

I collected lots of working experiences in hospitality field, therefore i chose to cut it off some from my resume, due to my working goal purposes.

If you are interested to check it out my full working experience, skills and certifications you can visit falker47/gituhub.io/myresume

**Note**: when it appears the icon next to an activity you can click on it to see the certification. You can click also on every underlined text to interact with it.

### **Freelance Activity**

O January 2023 - present day

#### **Private STEM Teacher**

I'm teaching physics and mathematics to High School students as a freelancer. So far I provided 300+ hours of lessons to 20+ students.

You can reach my Teacher Accounts on <u>LeTueLezioni</u> and <u>SuperProf</u> to check my students reviews, or my tutoring website that I developed on my own

## **Working Experience**

Settembre 2024 - presente

Banca Privata Leasing | Via Castaldi da Feltre, Reggio E. (RE), Italy

#### **CREDIT RISK ANALYST - Credit Assessment Department**

Portfolio analysis through financial and asset evaluations to determine creditworthiness and financing eligibility.

I also perform anti-money laundering checks to ensure regulatory compliance.

September 2023 - August 2024

Crédit Agricole | Via La Spezia 138/A, Parma (PR), Italy

#### **CREDIT RISK ANALYST**

As a member of Credit Risk Modeling Team, I've been working on the development of an Early Warning model with Artificial Intelligence techniques (Machine Learning).

I also contributed to the Data Collection project in order to analyze the financial stress exerted by Fit-for-55, the green-transition EU plan.

· Machine Learning, SAS, Datalku, SQL, Python, Excel, Powerpoint

February 2023 - January 2024

MasterZ | Corso di Porta Romana 61, 20122 Milan, Italy

### BLOCKCHAIN & DIGITAL ASSETS ACADEMY ATTENDEE



Winner of two scholarships, one for the 5th edition of the training course, and the another one for the BlockChain Project Lead specialization by AIO Blockchain Lab.

The following skills I learned, were put into practice in the development of a final project work, evaluated among the Top 50 of the entire course, and in the top 3 selected by Ernst&Young:

- Blockchain Technologies, Smart Contracts Notarization, Digital Assets (CBDC / crypto)
- DeFi, DApps, Centralized and Decentralized Exchanges

March 2023 - April 2023

Blazar Group | Via Besso 27, 6900 Lugano, Switzerland

### .NET FULL STACK ACADEMY ATTENDEE

Full-time training course (with project work) where I learned and implemented:

- C#, Azure, MSSQL for backend solutions
- HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, Angular for frontend solutions
- GitHub and Trello for the entire project task management

#### November 2017 - January 2022

Da Vittorio srl | Brusaporto (BG), Italy

#### 4th LEVEL CHEF

Job on call in occasion of important events where I was in charge of:

- Execution and Plating of Da Vittorio most famous dishes
- Cooking Line Preparation
- Public interaction